Hello everyone
I am Aite
Today I'm going to introduce
How to achieve multi-session parallelism in OpenClaw
You can achieve this through multiple Telegram groups or Discord channels
Of course, there is also a very simple method, which is the sub-agent
Within a single session, the agent can spawn multiple sub-agents for parallel processing.
By default, OpenClaw supports a maximum of 8 parallel sub-agents.
We can follow such prompts and let the AI assist you in completing the task.
First, let's introduce the configuration in Telegram
It supports configuring multiple chat sessions under the same bot.
DM, group is a chat group
group is the group owner
The same Bot can be configured with multiple chat sessions.
Any user sending a private message to the bot will form their own session.
configuration needs to be done through pairing
also supports multiple groups
Another approach is through forum topics
If all groups must require a default @mention to respond
you need to change the requireMention here to true
if a group responds without being @
then perform such a setting
The same Gateway can be configured with multiple Bots
the permissions of each Bot
you can adjust them all
If it's in Discord
It is very similar to Telegram
there are DMs and server channels
The same Bot can communicate with multiple users.
However, these DMs share the main session by default
So if you want to handle multiple tasks in parallel
it's best to use its server channels
This is a minimal configuration example
Finally, let's take a look at its detailed configuration guide.
In the previous video introducing OpenClaw
I mentioned through its source code
it was found that the maximum cross-session parallel processing number is 4, which you can adjust to other values as needed
Within a single session
The maximum number of parallel sub-agents is 8.
These are all adjustable according to your preferences.
Its session routing mechanism follows this pattern
If you want to configure it in Discord
First, create a dedicated server
Secondly, enable developer mode
then create and configure the bot
Create a new APP
In the key settings
It is recommended to disable the public bot
If it's just for your own use
disable this public bot
Please note the message content intent
This must be turned on
then
the bot can read the messages you send to it
Next,
we can then introduce the newly created bot
introduce to the service area
first via OAuth2
then let it generate a URL, with the scope covering these
The permissions for the Bot should all be enabled
After that, we can then connect to OpenClaw.
We can right-click the server's icon
Right-click the channel
Below is an example of the configuration
Now let's look at the Telegram configuration
You can add multiple Telegram groups to the whitelist
Each group will become an independent session
That's how it works
In the security configuration,
You can set it to only allow yourself to use it
For example, there is a DMpolicy
set its value to only allow private chats with whitelisted users
AllowFrom means only you can contact the Bot
groupAllowFrom only you can trigger the Bot in the group
Settings of BotFather
Here is the suggestion: enter /setjoingroups, select your Bot
Select your bot
select disable
prevent your bot from being added to other groups
Secondly, /setprivacy allows the Bot to see group messages.
Because in this group
I assume it's only you
and trusted individuals can use this Bot
and to allow the Bot to see group messages
when it's not necessary to directly @ it
we can modify the privacy settings here
To summarize, in order to use OpenClaw more securely in Discord
First, disable the public bot, and then set up a whitelist for the server.
channel whitelist
and user whitelist
In Telegram, you can restrict access to specified users or limit groups
You can also set it to prevent this bot from joining other groups
It was just mentioned about cross-session concurrency.
Supports up to 4 at maximum
You can set up 4 groups in Telegram
You can also set up 4 channels in Discord
or even more channels are all acceptable
as long as it does not exceed the system's default limit of 4 concurrent cross-session conversations
not exceeding the system's default setting of 4
that's acceptable
Let's take a look at some quick command references. After the configuration is complete,
You can restart the Gateway by using openclaw gateway restart
What issues may arise during the configuration process?
We can check the logs with 'openclaw logs --follow' to locate where the issue occurred.
Identify where the issue occurs
You can also view all sessions via openclaw sessions list
or use /subagents list to view subagents
In these configurations, the very important file locations are
The main one is the openclaw.json file
Another one is gateway.log.
That's all for today's introduction.